Guide to the Bob Johnson Papers, 1949-2003 CTC.2014.03
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Journals/Notebooks, ca.1960-1986; III.
  - PBTDE Job Descriptions, Duties, 48. (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Dept. of Black Studies, "Jammin'" Roller Skating, 49. (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - PBTDE Administration,Workshop Proposal, 50. (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Bitches Brew, Crit., Lyrics, 51. (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Jitney, Kuumba, African American Dance Class, 52. (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Talking Jazz, 53. (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - African American Dance, Talking Jazz, 54. (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Dance, Contacts, Talking Jazz Class, 55. (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Black Dance in America, 56. (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Black Dance, 57. (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Choreography, Dance, 58. (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Teaching, Promotion, Tenure, 59. (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Black Theater, Teaching, 60. (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - African Heritage Studies Assn., Travel, Lyrics, 61. (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Dance, Black America, 62. (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - African American Dance Class, 63. (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - PBTDE, 64. (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Journal, 65. (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - American Dreams, 66. (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Loose Journal, Observations, New York, 67. (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Unidentified Play Scenes, 68. (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Unidentified Play Scenes and Departmental Proposals, 69. (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Teaching and PBTDE, 70. (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Black Artists Today, Dance, 71. (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Dance, Professional Experience, 72. (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Theater Notes, 73. (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Loose Theater Notes, 74. (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Dance Education, 75. (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Choreography, 76. (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Nigeria Journal, Letter Drafts, 77. (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Mix Tapes, 78. (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - World Black and African Festival of Arts and Culture (FESTAC), Sun Ra, 1977; 79. (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Isis and Osiris, 80. (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - First Entrance poem, Drafts, 81. (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Paris Notebook, Choreography, 82. (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Puerto Rico Visit, 83. (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Unknown Script and Performance, 84. (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Isis, 1972; 85. (Box 3, Folder 79)
- Artistic and Professional Career, 1956-1996; IV.
  This series documents professional activities in Mr. Johnson's career over a 30 year period between 1955 and 1985. The first subseries relates to professional correspondence, while all remaining subseries contain manuscript, photographs and audiovisual material related to specific artistic roles inhabited by Bob Johnson during his career including dancer, choreographer, actor, director, and writer. Some examples of material in this series include ephemera and photographs from throughout his career including some of Mr. Johnson's earliest professional dance and instructor events as well as his time in the company for Hair. Also included are journals and correspondence from his time in Paris with the Dunham Company, scripts for plays that he choreographed like Liberty Avenue, acted in like Day of the Picnic, or directed like August Wilson's Jitney! The series also contains a number of poems and an autobiographical play entitled Plunk's Theme.
  - Correspondence, 1964-1986; 1.
    - Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Alvin Ailey, ca. 1974 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - American Foundation for the Science of Creative Intelligence, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - American Guild of Musical Artists, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - American Guild of Variety Artists, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Maisha Baton, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Jeanne Bromar, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Kelly Marie Berry, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - BlackFire Theatre, Birmingham Alabama, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Dr. Buffkins, University of Maryland, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Carnegie Library of Pittsburgh, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Jean Corrie Church, Hackley Collection, Detroit Public Library, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Dance Uhuru, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - Peter Deanda, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - Delta Sigma Theta Sorority Inc., 1985 (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - James A. Devinney, Metropolitan Pittsburgh Public Broadcasting Inc., 1979 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - Lucille Ellis, Dunham School, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - Eugene O'Neill Memorial Theater, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - Samuel A. Foster, Fisk University, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 98)
    - Mary Folberg, Portland Public Schools, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - Martha Glaser, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - James B. Gwynne, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - Nancy Hanks, National Council of the Arts, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Harambee of Pittsburgh, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - Richard and Janice Harris, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - Ruther Henderson, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - Carole Y. Johnson, 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - Majorie Johnson, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - Kris Keiser, Ksiser Productions Inc., 1974 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - Dawn Ketterman, Monavian College, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - Yusef Komonyakaa, University of New Orleans, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Jean Bryant Lawson, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Richard Long, Atlanta University, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - Bayo Martins, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Margaret Matthews, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Modern Organization for Dance Evolvement (M.O.D.E.) Inc., 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - William Moore, Black Theatre Alliance, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - Clyde Morgan, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - Morton Winston School of Dance, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - Novella Nelson, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - New Lafayette Theatre, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - New York Public Library, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - Stanze Peterson (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - Philadelphia School of Dance, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - Rosalind Pierson, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - Pittsburgh Dance Council, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - Diana Ramos, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Schenley High School, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Ruth Schoenfeld, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Ben Shaktman, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - Maxine Strawder (M.O.D.E. Regional Dance Conference), 1972 (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Maxine Strawder, 1971-1985 (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - Society of Stage Directors and Choreographers Inc., ca. 1970 (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - Dick Thornburgh, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - Carl H. Tillman, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - University of the West Indies, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Vantile, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - Linda F. Wharton, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 138)
    - Pat Washington, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - Lauren Webb, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - David F. Wynn, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - Dancer, 1956-1986; 2.
    - Early Professional Activity, 1956-1965
      - Flyer, Delinquent Line Up: A New Musical Review, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 142)
      - Program, Afro Arts Cultural Centre Presents New York City Winter Festival of the Arts, Stanze Peterson Dance Company, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 143)
      - Program, Benefit performance sponsored by the Frederick Douglass House Council, Stanze Peterson Dance Company (Box 3, Folder 144)
      - Program, Creations, New Dancers (Box 3, Folder 145)
    - Katherine Dunham Company, 1965-1968
      - Contracts, Office de Radiodiffusion Télévision Française, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 146)
      - Journal, Katherine Dunham Company: Paris, France, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 147)
      - Script, Deux Anges sont Venus, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 148)
      - Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 149)
      - Ephemera, Paris, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 150)
      - Contract, Apollo Theatre, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 151)
      - Photographs, Deux Anges Sont Venus at Theatre De Paris, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 59)
      - Photographs, Chaka, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 60)
      - Photographs, Paris Studio Portraits and Negatives, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 61)
      - Photographs, La Vie Quotidienne, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 62)
      - Photographs, Unidentified Film Shoot, ca. 1967 (Box 11, Folder 63)
      - Photographs, Unidentified Parisian Performance and Negatives, ca. 1967 (Box 11, Folder 64)
      - Photographs, Outdoor Paris Portraits, ca. 1966 (Box 11, Folder 65-66)
      - Photographs, Outdoor Paris Candids, ca. 1966 (Box 11, Folder 67)
      - Photographs, Outdoor Paris Portraits (Oversized), 1966 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Hair, 1966-1979
      - Audition Flyer, ca. 1966 (Box 3, Folder 152)
      - Contracts, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 153)
      - Script, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, ca. 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Programs, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Press, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Photographs, Hair, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 67)
      - Photographs, Hair (Oversized), ca. 1967-1968 (Box 14, Folder 11)
      - Hair Film Program (Oversized), 1979 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Harlem Cultural Council Dancemobile, 1968-1969
      - Contract, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Press, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Progress Report by Carole Y. Johnson, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Flyer, Summer on Wheels (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Photographs, Soloist in Eleo Pomare's Beginsville and Assassination by Rod Rogers, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 68)
    - Second Annual World Black and African Festival of Arts and Culture (FESTEC), 1977-1979
      - Newsletters, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Memo and Reports, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Press Clippings, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Osun Festival Invitation, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Ephemera, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Notes and Writings, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 15-16)
      - Press, 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - Photographs, FESTEC in Nigeria and Slides, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 69-79)
    - Sun Ra and His Space Arkestra, ca. 1976-1980
      - Sun Ra Space Arkestra International Tour by Greg Mims, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - Photographs, Sun Ra Tour with Negatives, ca. 1976-1980 (Box 11, Folder 80-87)
      - Photographs, Sun Ra Tour of Italy, 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 88-89)
      - Posters, Sun Ra (Oversized), ca. 1979 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Assorted Dance Work, ca.1965-1986
      - Dunham Technique Seminar, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Erika Thimey Dance Theatre (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - "Phantasia" A Benefit Performance Starring Lendina Wright (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - The Virginia Dance Society presents the Dance Society of Washington D.C. (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - Vann's Founder's Day program (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - Urban League Sunday, Late Afternoon and Still Singing, Urban League of Pittsburgh, February 9, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - Curriculum Vitae, 1973-1983 (Box 4, Folder 25)
      - Photographs, Elements Dance (Box 11, Folder 90)
      - Poster, Kuumba Na Nia Dance Theater (Oversize), ca. 1975 (Map-case 25-6, Oversize 1)
      - Photographs, Miscellaneous Johnson Performing, ca.1965-1986 (Box 11, Folder 91)
    - Instructor, ca. 1966-1985
      - Flyer, Dance Class, Afram Cultural Arts Center Studio-O Brooklyn, ca. 1967 (Box 4, Folder 26)
      - Madu, ca. 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - Flyer, Madu Academy III, ca. 1966-1969 (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - Project Self Esteem program and thank you letters, ca. 1970 (Box 4, Folder 29)
      - Spirited Dance Workshop, Selma Burke Art Center, ca. 1970-1980 (Box 4, Folder 30)
      - Spirited Dance Workshop, Selma Burke Art Center, Master Print for Flyers (Oversized) (Box 14, Folder 14)
      - Thank you poem, Selma Burke Art Center (Oversized), ca.1972 (Box 14, Folder 15)
      - Afro American Performing Arts Workshop (Box 4, Folder 31)
      - Kuumba Na Nia Workshops (Box 4, Folder 32)
      - Roller Skating Dance Workshop, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Choreographer, 1971-1985; 3.
    - The Black Terror, 1971
      - Contract, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 34)
      - Script, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 35)
      - Script, Bob Johnson's Copy, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 36)
      - Press, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 37)
      - Society of Stage Directors and Choreographers, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 38)
      - Royalty Statements, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - First National Congress on Blacks in Dance, 1973
      - Congress Packet, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 40)
      - Master Class recap, June 28, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 41)
      - Who's Who biography, June 28, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 42)
      - Photographs, First National Congress on Blacks in Dance, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - How Do You Spell Watergait?, 1976
      - Contract, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 43)
      - Script, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 44)
      - Press, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 45)
      - Photographs, How Do You Spell Watergait?, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Poster, How Do You Spell Watergait? (Oversized), 1976 (Box 14, Folder 16)
      - Poster, How Do You Spell Watergait? (Oversized), 1976 (Map-case 25-6, Oversize 2)
    - Bitches Brew, 1978
      - Program, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 46)
      - Press Release, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 47)
      - Press Clippings, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 48)
      - Photographs, Bitches Brew, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 3-4)
    - Black Bart and the Sacred Hills, 1977-1978
      - Draft Synopsis (Box 4, Folder 49)
      - Pre-Production, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 50)
      - Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 51)
      - Correspondence, Claude Purdy, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 52)
      - Script, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 53)
      - Flyer, Auditions, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 54)
      - Readers Theatre Run-Through, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - Correspondence, New York Shakespeare Festival, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Who Loves the Dancer?, 1982
      - Script, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 57)
      - Programs, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 58)
      - Press, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Lysistrata, 1982
      - Script, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 60)
      - Program, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Liberty Avenue, 1984
      - Contract (Box 4, Folder 62)
      - Script, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 63)
      - Cast Listing, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 64)
      - Rehearsal Schedule, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 65)
      - Choreography Notes, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 66)
      - Flyers, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 67)
      - Program, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 68)
      - Press, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Give the Drummer Some, 1985
      - Copyright Agreement, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 70)
      - Script, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Assorted Choreographic Work, 1971-1985
      - Showcase for Young Choreographers, Pittsburgh Dance Council, March 8, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 72)
      - YWCA Contract, March 1971 (Box 4, Folder 73)
      - YWCA Workshop on Dance and Drama of Minority Groups program and workbook, July 1971 (Box 4, Folder 74)
      - Program, Black Action Society Theatre Lucifer's Boogie, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 75)
      - Why, Baby Why?, Carnegie Mellon University Project Upward Bound, July 31, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 76)
      - Black Expressions!, March 1977 (Box 4, Folder 77)
      - Poster, Black Expressions! (Oversized), March 1977 (Box 14, Folder 17)
      - Audition Flyer, Love Potion A Disco Dance Collage, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 78)
      - Program, A Touch of Fashion Extravaganza, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 79)
      - Celebration of Men in Dance, New York Community College program and press release, April 1980 (Box 4, Folder 80)
      - Script, Innerspace, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 81)
      - Brecht on Brecht, University of Pittsburgh Theatre, February 1983 (Box 4, Folder 82)
      - Posters, University of Pittsburgh Theatre Arts, ca. 1980 (Map-case 25-6, Oversize 3)
      - Contract, Delta Sigma Theta Sorority Inc., 1984 (Box 4, Folder 83)
      - Program, Celebration of Men in Dance Part III Honoring Male Dancers of the 60s, Brooklyn Academy of Music, with autographs, May 5, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 84)
      - Program, Choreographer' Continium II, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 85)
      - Press Release Petals (Box 4, Folder 86)
      - Choreography Illustrations (Box 4, Folder 87)
      - Cisco Kid Costume Designs (Box 4, Folder 88)
      - Assorted Press, ca. 1970-1981 (Box 4, Folder 89)
      - Photographs, Roller Skate Dance Practice (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Photographs, Ritual of Damballah (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - Photographs, The Fish That Saved Pittsburgh with Slides, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Actor, 1973-1984; 4.
    - National Playwright's Conference, 1973
      - Conference Material, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - The O'Neil Scene Seen v.5 no.9, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Midnight, 1982
      - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Poster, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Press Release, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Press Clippings, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Day of the Picnic, 1984
      - Contract, City Theatre Company, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Rehearsal and Performance Schedule, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Script, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
      - Program, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Press Clippings, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Assorted Acting Work, 1967-1985
      - Program, Goin' A Buffalo, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Program, Black Horizon Theatre, Centre Avenue, A Trip, May 1971 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Poster, Black Horizon Theatre, Centre Avenue, A Trip (Oversize), 1971 (Box 14, Oversize 18)
      - Program, American Ibsen Theater, Long Marriages, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - Photographs, Black Happenin' with Negatives, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Poster, Black Happenin' (Oversize), 1967 (Box 14, Oversize 19)
  - Director, 1978-1996; 5.
    - Jitney, 1978-1996
      Johnson directed the world premiere production of August Wilson's Jitney in October and November, 1982. It was performed at the Fine Line Cultural Center in Oakland as a part of the Allegheny Repertory Theatre's 1982/1983 season. The production's cast was composed of local actors and community leaders, including Sala Udin. Photographs in this series include actors Claude Purdy as Becker, Ronald Pitts as Fielding, Milton Thompson as Turnbo, Gwendolyn Perry as Rena, Buck Price as The Man, and Monte Russell as Youngblood. There is also one folder of photographs from the 1996 production of Jitney at the Pittsburgh Public Theater.
      - Performance Permission from August Wilson, March 4, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Correspondence, August Wilson, ca. 1978-1982 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Contracts, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - Cast and Crew, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - Director's Notes, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - Finances, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - Artwork, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - Set Design, July 1983 (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - Posters and Flyers, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 24)
      - Performance poster (Oversize), 1983 (Map-case 25-6, Oversize 2)
      - Booster/Becker Scene Rewrite, October 1982 (Box 5, Folder 25)
      - Annotated Scripts, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 26-30)
      - Programs, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 31)
      - Press Clippings, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 32)
      - Photographs, Jitney and Slides, 1982-1983 (Box 12, Folder 9-15)
      - Photographs, Jitney Pittsburgh Public Theater Production, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Nongogo, 1985
      - Script, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 33)
      - Program, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 34)
      - Stage Notes, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 35)
      - Promotional Material, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Assorted Directing and Production Works, 1971-1984
      - El Hajj Malik, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 37-38)
      - Script, Selma Burke Art Center's The Wiz (Box 5, Folder 39)
      - Hues of Langston, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 40)
      - Choices II, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 41-42)
      - Program, Little Black Boys (Box 5, Folder 43)
      - Brief Portfolio Poetry Collage (Box 5, Folder 44)
      - Poster, Brief Portfolio Poetry Collage (Oversized), March 1980 (Box 14, Folder 20)
      - Community Communication Conference on Local Cable Directing and Producing, ca. 1983 (Box 5, Folder 45)
      - Grant, Blacks in Pittsburgh: A Chronology, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Writer, 1971-1985; 6.
    - Poetry, 1971-1985
      - African Footprints, 1981-1985 (Box 5, Folder 47)
      - Audition (Box 5, Folder 48)
      - First Entrance (Prayer) (Box 5, Folder 49)
      - For the First Time: Liberation Dance (Box 5, Folder 50)
      - Freedom |Unity Dance No. 1, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 51)
      - Gypsy Lady (Box 5, Folder 52)
      - Hang Tough (Box 5, Folder 53)
      - A Message to Black Feet (Box 5, Folder 54)
      - Murder #1 (Box 5, Folder 55)
      - New Dance|Caberet|Dance Discipline No. 9 (Box 5, Folder 56)
      - Original Dance Machine (Box 5, Folder 57)
      - Dance Machine, Pittsburgh Courier Poetry Contest (Oversize), 1979 (Map-case 25-6, Oversize 2)
      - Peek A Boo, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 58)
      - Rapture Dance, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 59)
      - Theme for Babara From Prison Ritual 1972 For Thomas Hicks and Attica 1971 (Box 5, Folder 60)
      - Untitled (Box 5, Folder 61)
      - Untitled, April 30, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Plays and Skits, ca. 1971-1986
      - The Adventures of the Astral Pirates (A Musical Space Comedy): A Theatrical Stage Treatment by Bob Johnson (Box 5, Folder 63)
      - The Legend of Marimba (Box 5, Folder 64)
      - The Loose Booty Sisters (Box 5, Folder 65)
      - Love on Wheels (Box 5, Folder 66)
      - Plunk's Theme (Box 5, Folder 67)
      - Several Shades of Mama (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Essays, ca. 1971-1986
      - A Choreographer's Comment (Box 5, Folder 69)
      - Where We Stand Now (Box 5, Folder 70)
      - Untitled (The Function of Black Dance Instruction) (Box 5, Folder 71)
- Pittsburgh Black Theatre Dance Ensemble and Theatre Urge, 1970-1985; V.
  The Pittsburgh Black Theatre Dance series has manuscript, photographic, and audiovisual items pertaining to the history of the arts company founded by Bob Johnson in 1970. The company's goal was to explore and uplift the people of the Black Diaspora through the performing arts. Johnson served as artistic director of the company for many years with the core leadership team and faculty that included, Linda F. Wharton, who later went on to become artistic director of the company, Oliver Byrd, Linda Herring, Sherry Hoard, Bill Johnson, Maliki Roberts and Malaya Rucker. The series provides general information on the company as a whole as well as its subsidiary group the Afro American Dance Center and acting arm Theatre Urge. Specific materials include company by-laws and board meeting minutes, correspondence, ephemera, press, photographs and audiovisual material.
  - History and Administration, 1972-1982; 1.
    - History, ca. 1970-1979 (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Statement of Purpose (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - By-Laws, ca. 1972 (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - Constitution (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - Membership Card (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - Articles of Incorporation, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - Tax Exemption, January 1972 (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - Copyright Registration, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - Job Descriptions (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - Artist Biographies (Box 5, Folder 81)
    - Board of Directors, 1972-1975 (Box 5, Folder 82-85)
    - Staff, Linda F. Wharton, 1974-1979 (Box 5, Folder 86)
    - Board of Directors, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - Theatre Urge: Report to the Executive Council, January 28, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 88)
    - Planning Proposals, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 89)
    - Board of Directors, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 90-91)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 92)
    - Board of Directors, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 93)
    - Internship report, Byram Johns, 1981-1984 (Box 5, Folder 94)
  - Finances, 1971-1982; 2.
    - Ledger/Journal, 1971-1982 (Box 5, Folder 95)
    - Equipment Proposal (Box 5, Folder 96)
    - Performance Fees (Box 5, Folder 97)
    - Funding Sources (Box 5, Folder 98)
    - A Financial Look at the Pittsburgh Black Theatre Dance Ensemble, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 99)